

Raynald Saputra
Electrical and Computer Engineering

About me

Graduated from Electrical and Computer Engineering, Satya Wacana Christian University (UKSW) in 2022. Throughout my education, I established a strong foundation in electrical and computer engineering, especially in building a website based on HTML, and CSS. Possessed programming language skills such as C++, Python, Arduino and low level ones such as Assembly, and machine level language. I was involved in student leadership training as a leader in 2017. That valuable experience has strengthened my leadership, teamwork, public speaking, critical thinking, and problem solving skills.

Personal Information

Place/Date and Birth : Bandar Lampung / 2 Mei 1997

Age : 25 years old

Gender : Male

Nationality : Indonesia

Experience

- Freelance at duamusim as Developer in Dec 2022 until Now
 - Assist building a website https://duamusim.id/home
 - Sharpen at skills as Developer. Sharpen at team work skills, and problem solving skills.
- Participated in Progate Frontend Developer Course in 2022
 - Learnt about HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Git for building a Website
 - Make some website design one page at https://raynaldsaputra.github.io/progateTest2/
- Participated in Digital Talent Scholarship by KOMINFO in 2019 about Machine Learning
 - Learnt basic Machine Learning using Python programming language and AWS Products.
- Internship at FX.Marsudirini 78 Primary School as Electrical & Robotic Teacher
 (May 2018 August 2018)
 - Created electronic and robotic mini projects to enthuse students to be interested in electronic or robotic fields.

- Created a teaching method for students to understand electronic and robotic fields more easily.

Student Body functionary of Faculty of Electrical and Computer Engineering – SWCU (Apr 2017 – Jul 2018)

- Optimize intership program by restructuring and regulating the Student Body's guidelines.
- Created activity point system to grow student interactivity, and to increase cadres' involvement in campus organization.
- Learn to work both in teams and at individual level to quickly adapt in new environment. Practised analytical thinking and sharpened robust work ethic.

Coordinator of Student Leadership Basic Training (2017) in the FTEK SWCU

- Arranged basic student leadership training for 45 students which was held for 4 days.
- Led and managed about 15 people to achieve event goals and complete programs.
- Collaborated with team to grow student sense of leadership especially in critical thinking, leading team, time management and teamwork by adding team building sessions.
- Achieved Leadership skill, people coordinating ability, both team and individual work.
 Strengthened public speaking, analytical thinking and critical thinking skills to solve problems.

Skills

- HTML 5
- CSS 3
- C++
- JavaScript
- Python (Basic)
- Microcontroller and IOT (Arduino, ESP8266)
- PLC (Basic)

Education

Satya Wacana Christian University (2015-2022) S1-Electrical Engineer (with GPA 3.08)

Project

Prototype of Microgreen Cultivation Automation based on IOT

Built a prototype of Microgreen Cultivation Automation based on Microcontroller Arduino and IOT integrated with various sensors and devices. Users can control and monitor the system via a touch screen LCD or via smartphone with BLYNK App.

• Website with responsive at progate.com courses

Built a website with determined design when following the course at progate.com with HTML and CSS. The website can be responsive at smartphone or tab. Users can visit the link at https://raynaldsaputra.github.io/progateTest2/